{
    "title": "C programming language",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question_text": "Which of the following statements should be used to obtain a remainder after dividing 3.14 by 2.1 ?",
            "answer": "C",
            "variants": [
                "A. rem = 3.14 % 2.1;",
                "B. rem = modf(3.14, 2.1);",
                "C. rem = fmod(3.14, 2.1);",
                "D. Remainder cannot be obtain in floating point division."
            ]
        },
        {
            "question_text": "What are the types of linkages?",
            "answer": "B",
            "variants": [
                "A. Internal and External",
                "B. External, Internal and None",
                "C. External and None",
                "D. Internal"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question_text": "Which of the following special symbol allowed in a variable name?",
            "answer": "D",
            "variants": [
                "A. * (asterisk)",
                "B. | (pipeline)",
                "C. - (hyphen)",
                "D. _ (underscore)"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question_text": "When we mention the prototype of a function?",
            "answer": "B",
            "variants": [
                "A.Defining",
                "B.Declaring",
                "C.Prototyping",
                "D.Calling"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question_text": "Is there any difference between following declarations?\n1 :extern int fun();\n2 : int fun();",
            "answer": "B",
            "variants": [
                "A. Both are identical",
                "B. No difference, except extern int fun(); is probably in another file",
                "C. int fun(); is overrided with extern int fun();",
                "D. None of these"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question_text": "How would you round off a value from 1.66 to 2.0?",
            "answer": "A",
            "variants": [
                "A. ceil(1.66)",
                "B. floor(1.66)",
                "C. roundup(1.66)",
                "D. roundto(1.66)"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question_text": "By default a real number is treated as a",
            "answer": "B",
            "variants": [
                "A. float",
                "B. double",
                "C. long double",
                "D. far double"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question_text": "Is the following statement a declaration or definition?\nextern int i;",
            "answer": "A",
            "variants": [
                "A. Declaration",
                "B. Definition",
                "C. Function",
                "D. Error"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question_text": "Identify which of the following are declarations\n1 : extern int x;\n2 : float square ( float x ) { ... }\n3 : double pow(double, double);",
            "answer": "C",
            "variants": [
                "A. 1",
                "B. 2",
                "C. 1 and 3",
                "D. 3"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question_text": "Which of the following functions can be used to increase the size of dynamically allocated array?",
            "answer": "A",
            "variants": [
                "A. realloc()",
                "B. calloc()",
                "C. malloc()",
                "D. memadjust()"
            ]
        }
    ]
}